Ernest Blumenschein papers
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Printed Materials, 1891-1964, Series 6:; (Box 2, OV1; 0.5 linear feet)
  The bulk of this series has been scanned, except for news clippings printed reproductions of artwork and business cards. In some cases, only the covers and title pages for exhibition catalogs have been scanned.
  - Blumy's Taos Tournament, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Business Cards, circa 1900s-1930s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, 1896-1899, (4 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 43-46)
  - Clippings, 1890s, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Clippings, 1900-1909, (5 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 48-52)
  - Clippings, 1900s, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 53-54)
  - Clippings, 1910-1919, (9 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 55-63)
  - Clippings, 1910s, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Clippings, 1920-1929, (13 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 65-77)
  - Clippings, 1920s, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 78-80)
  - Clippings, 1930-1939, (10 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 81-90)
  - Clippings, 1930s, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 91-92)
  - Clippings, 1940-1949, (8 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 93-100)
  - Clippings, 1940s, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 101-103)
  - Clippings, 1950-1959, (12 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 104-115)
  - Clippings, circa 1950s, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 116-117)
  - Clippings, 1960-1964, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 118-120)
  - Clippings, circa 1960s, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1927-1958 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Exhibition Catalogs [Fragments], circa 1920s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Invitations, circa 1930s-1958 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - National Academy of Design, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Postcards, circa 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, 1891-1898 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, 1900-1911, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, 1915-1930, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1890s-1910s, (4 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 131-134)
  - Reproductions of Artwork: Mary Blumenschein, circa 1900s-1920s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Reproductions of Artwork: Others, circa 1910s-1930s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Salmagundi Club, 1902, (Oversized item housed in OV1) (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - School Of American Research, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Taos Heptagon, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Salmagundi Club, 1902, (Scanned with Box 2, F137) (Box OV1)
- Photographs, 1880s-1955, Series 7:; (Box 2, OV1; 0.25 linear feet)
  Photographs include two portraits of Ernest Blumenschein, a photograph of Blumenschein with other members of the National Academy of Design, and exhibition/installation views at the Art Institute of Chicago, the Carnegie Institute, and a Colorado post office. The bulk of the photographs are of artwork by Blumenschein, including paintings, murals, and student work. Also found are photographs of artwork by others including Oscar Berninghaus and E. Martin Hennings.
  Photographs of artwork have not been scanned.
  - Ernest Blumenschein, 1924-1930 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Artwork, circa 1893, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Artwork, 1906-1907, (Oversized item housed in OV1; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Artwork, 1912-1919, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Artwork, circa 1910s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Artwork, 1920-1924, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Artwork, 1926-1929, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Artwork, circa 1920s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Artwork, 1931-1934, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Artwork, 1935-1939, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Artwork, circa 1930s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Artwork, 1941-1949, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Artwork, circa 1940s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Artwork, 1955, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Artwork By Others, circa 1910s-1930s, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Artwork Installation, 1912-1945 (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - National Academy of Design, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Unknown Subject, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - Negatives (Box 2)
    - Ernest Blumenschein, 1927, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - Artwork, 1937, (Not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - Artwork, 1906, (see also Box 2, F142; not scanned) (Box OV1)